The year 2027: the last days of the human race. No child has been
born for 18 years. He must protect our only hope.
Children of Men is a drama, action, thriller film directed by Alfonso Cuarón.
In 2027, in a chaotic world in which humans can no longer procreate, a former activist agrees to help transport a miraculously
pregnant woman to a sanctuary at sea, where her child's birth may help scientists save the future of humankind.
Theo Faron, played by Clive Owen.
Kee, played by Clare-Hope Ashitey.
Luke, played by Chiwetel Ejiofor.
Julian, played by Julianne Moore.
Jasper, played by Michael Caine.
Miriam, played by Pam Ferris.
Children of Men is a 2006 dystopian action thriller film
directed and co-written by Alfonso Cuarón.
The screenplay, based on P.
James' 1992 novel The Children of Men, was credited to five
writers, with Clive Owen making uncredited contributions.
The film is set in 2027, when two decades of human infertility have
left human civilisation on the brink of collapse.
Asylum seekers seek sanctuary in the United Kingdom, where they are
subjected to detention and  deportation by the government.
Owen plays civil servant Theo Faron, who tries to help
refugee Kee (Clare-Hope Ashitey) escape the chaos.
Children of Men also stars Julianne Moore, Chiwetel Ejiofor,
Pam Ferris, Charlie Hunnam, and Michael Caine.
The film was released by Universal Pictures on 22 September
2006, in the UK and on 25 December in the US.
Despite the limited release and lack of any clear marketing strategy during awards season by the film's distributor, Children of Men received critical
acclaim and was recognised for its achievements in screenwriting, cinematography, art direction, and innovative single-shot action sequences.
While it underperformed at the box office, it was nominated for three Academy Awards:
Best Adapted Screenplay, Best Cinematography, and Best Film Editing.
It was also nominated for three BAFTA Awards, winning Best Cinematography and Best
Production Design, and for three Saturn Awards, winning Best Science Fiction Film.
It was voted 13th in a BBC critics’ poll on the best films released
between 2000 and 2016 by film critics from around the world.
The film explores themes of future, government, police
state, based on novel or book, hippie.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking and intense.